[opening theme music playing]
[electronic warbling]
[tense music playing]
[waves crashing]
[thunder rumbling]
Thanapod! Leeward side!
[intense music playing]
[sailors clamoring]
[grunting]
[sailor yelling, grunting]
[thanapod screeching]
[sailor 2 grunting]
[ax whooshing]
[thanapod screeching]
[sailor 2 screaming]
[thanapod warbling]
[sailor 3 yelling]
[sailor 3 groaning, gurgling]
-[thanapod screeching]
-[sailor 3 screaming]
[loud thumping, clattering]
[retching, vomiting]
[suspenseful music playing]
I believe this to be the only fair way.
Off you go, Cert.
Go on now.
[man exhaling sharply]
[Cert sighing heavily]
[suspenseful music swelling]
-[Cert sighing]
-Steady on.
Thank you, Mr. Melis.
[wincing]
[Melis groaning]
Thank Cerval!
Thank Cerval.
[ship creaking]
So, now that we've chosen a leader…
I will be picking who goes.
[sailors grunting, struggling]
[groaning] All right! All right.
You needn't manhandle me further.
I go willingly.
I shall report what I see.
Yeah. Do that.
Good luck.
[sighing] Wonderful.
[tense music playing]
[breath shuddering]
[ship creaking]
[water sloshing]
[suspenseful music playing]
[chains rattling]
[squelching]
-[thanapod screeching]
-[man yelling]
[man panting]
[thanapod growling]
[distorted voice] Phaiden Island.
Beg your pardon?
Take me.
-[squelching]
-Oh.
Me eat meat.
-Oh my.
-Me eat meat.
Of course.
[squelching]
But first,
you and I must come to an agreement.
-[squelching]
-[thanapod chittering]
Most importantly,
I am the only one
who can keep this ship on a straight keel.
Me, you need intact.
Unconsumed.
Do you understand?
Good.
Now, there is one more thing you have…
which I shall require.
[creature squawking]
[seals barking]
-[shark growling]
-[seal whimpering]
[thanopod growling, gurgling]
-[objects clattering]
-Ugh.
[thanopod clambering]
[thanopod gurgling]
[squelching]
[unnerving music playing]
-[knocking on door]
-[yelps]
[knocking on door]
[waves crashing]
[door creaking]
[man] Hello.
[suspenseful music playing]
[man 2] What happened?
[man exhaling sharply]
[man 2] Torrin!
[Torrin breathing heavily]
[Torrin grunting]
[groaning, straining]
I negotiated with it…
as you must now with me.
Listen carefully,
I am in no mood to repeat myself.
The thing speaks.
You had a conversation with a crustacean?
Which I haven't the patience to explain
beyond saying that it wants passage
to the nearest island.
We saw that beast do
exactly what it pleased.
[panting]
You'd have us believe
you will go up against it?
If, in fact, we do transport it
in the hopes it will spare our lives,
we have nothing substantial to feed it.
And as it has acquired a taste for…
[footsteps approaching]
[man grunting]
What about him then?
He's already half done, isn't he?
Yeah, he looks quite unwell.
He's half more alive
than anyone else will be
that points a crooked finger
at my brother.
Enough!
[sighing heavily]
We reside together in this misfortune.
Which puts us right back where we started.
-Huh?
-But, Chantre, you are correct.
We find ourselves faced again
with a grim and terrible decision.
Unless
it's already been made.
[bird squawking]
[unnerving music playing]
[gulping]
[sailors grunting, straining]
[man yelling]
[man moaning]
-[thanopod clambering]
-[man screaming]
-[thanopod growling]
-[squelching]
That's it.
Every last bite.
[crunching]
[Torrin sighing]
Phaiden Island.
This is where it wants to be taken.
With the wind at our backs,
it's still another day and a half.
And allowing this thanapod ashore
would mean unleashing it
on unsuspecting Phaiden citizenry.
Sounds good.
[scoffing]
Just as soon spit on you as nod,
in my experience.
That happened to me.
Twice.
Nevertheless,
I propose another possibility.
These nameless islands
further on are deserted.
We may be able to take the monster there
without it even realizing.
This course of action offers a chance
at sparing countless innocent lives.
[ship creaking]
Fine, we shall put it to a vote.
Each of you will have equal voice.
It will be a secret ballot with no man
knowing any other man's choice.
You will privately mark
and fold your ballots,
then return them to me.
A circle will indicate a vote
to sail beyond the peopled shores
despite the risk.
And an X is a vote
for a shorter voyage to Phaiden Island.
X means you fulfill the creature's wish.
[suspenseful music playing]
Let conscience be your guide.
[ominous whooshing]
[seagulls warbling]
I begin with a confession.
By a folded corner here,
an irregular edge there,
I made each of these ballots unique,
unbeknownst to anyone but myself.
Having paid strict attention
as I handed them out, the duty falls to me
to reveal I have succeeded
in ferreting out the cowards in our midst.
-W-what did he say?
-He said there are cowards.
Craven cowards
who would gladly betray a stranger
if it meant saving their own skin.
Two cowards
who voted to pass our terrible burden
to the defenseless men,
women, and children of Phaiden Island.
-Mr. Melis, step to your right, please.
-Excuse me?
He said, "Step to your right."
Okay.
Very kind, thank you.
[men grunting, gasping]
-[suspenseful music playing]
-[gasping]
Done and done.
Nearly as unpleasant as it was necessary.
United we are at last,
in spirit, goal, and purpose.
Mr. Suparin, adjust our course please.
[all breathing heavily]
[unnerving music playing]
[music swelling]
[thanopod clambering]
[thanopod screeching]
Double the meal,
double the time in between.
[squelching]
One would hope.
[ship creaking]
[suspenseful music playing]
[scribbling]
[gun cocking]
[gasping]
[man] Wait, sir. Please!
[breath shuddering]
They made me.
[thanopod] Torrin.
-[thanopod clambering]
-[thanopod] Torrin!
Torrin!
[gun uncocking]
[squelching]
[chains rattling]
You rang?
Phaiden Island.
Yes.
Patience is the word of the day.
We are well on our way--
[chittering]
[thanopod] Hungry.
Hungry.
[suspenseful music swelling]
Of course.
So many mouths to feed.
Must eat soon.
We must eat.
Hmm.
There lies Phaiden Island.
Closer by the minute.
I am willing to see
the failed attempt on my life
as an expression of low morale,
but this nightmare is very nearly
at an end.
I swear it.
And tomorrow, sir?
If your friend below us gets--
Maintain course!
And wake me at the toll of the hour.
[tense music playing]
[footsteps approaching]
[suspenseful music swelling]
[sizzling]
[sailors grunting, yelling]
[sailors panting]
Huh?
[floor creaking]
[gun cocking]
[intense music playing]
[grunting]
[gun cocking]
[man grunting]
[Torrin grunting]
[man 2 yelling, groaning]
[Torrin groaning, wincing]
[squelching]
[clattering]
[yelping]
I refused to participate.
And for that I am grateful.
[thanopod clambering]
[unnerving music playing]
[squelching]
[chittering]
[Torrin] In the spirit of fairness,
I lied before. [panting]
I didn't actually mark the ballots.
[thudding]
I didn't have to.
[man] Whoa, whoa.
Whoa! [yelling]
Every one of you made an X.
[crunching]
[exhaling slowly]
[bird squawking]
[Torrin] We've arrived!
Show yourself.
Phaiden Island.
[Torrin] Yes.
As you know,
there's not much good eating
on a jable shark.
The meat
is greasy.
[gurgling]
[Torrin] And the hide
is too tough for any garment.
[gurgling]
But what they do have in abundance…
is oil.
Shell protects.
It's not for you.
[thanopod screeching]
[suspenseful music swelling]
[intense music playing]
[Torrin gasping, grunting]
[thanopod screeching
[Torrin grunting]
[ship cracking]
[thanopod screeching]
[breathing heavily]
[breath shuddering]
[straining]
[grunting]
[music fades]
[electronic warbling]
[closing theme music playing]
[music fades]