[opening theme music playing]
[electronic warbling]
[bagpipe music playing]
[vehicle whirring]
[chickens clucking]
[liquid pouring]
-[rats squeaking]
-[man groaning]
I see ya, ya twitty wee shite.
[vehicles whirring]
[man] Bloody hell.
[cat screeches]
-[cat scurrying]
-Hey!
-[hissing]
-[gun firing]
Take that, ya nasty bastard.
[ominous music playing]
What the fuck is that?
[suspenseful music playing]
[phone beeping]
Aye, it's Mason.
Do you know a good pest control company?
[music fades]
Yeah. Mm-hmm. Yeah. Oh. Right.
Well, no need to worry, Mr. Mason.
Traptech can solve
your little rat problem.
Little?
It's an armed rat fucking rebellion,
is what it is.
-[chuckling] Well, no.
-[cat purring]
We're seeing quite a lot of this lately,
Mr. Mason.
Evolution, you see.
Humanity is warping the environment,
forcing the animal kingdom to adapt,
et cetera, et cetera.
A certain level of tool use
is nothing to worry about.
Aye, aye.
Less Darwinian theory,
more rodent-killing hardware.
-Allow me to introduce the TT6.
-[dramatic music playing]
A fixed-position, guided pulse laser
with sensors that can zero a woodlouse
at a kilometer.
The very latest in Traptech-nology.
With just four of these killing machines
in each barn,
and you really can "Fire and Forget."
[sighing heavily]
How much?
Do I really need all this shite?
Is this not a bit fucking overkill?
Well, you can't be too careful
when it comes to pest control, Mr. Mason.
-And Barn One systems are online.
-[electronic trilling]
[electronic warbling]
Oh! We've got a kill already.
[chuckling] How about that? Look at that.
[cat meowing]
Ah, yes.
We do advise that you keep other animals
clear of the kill zone.
-Her name was Susan.
-[melancholy music playing]
[voice breaking] And I'll be expecting
a discount for that.
[thudding]
[guns zapping]
[dramatic music playing]
[Mason chuckling]
[guns zapping]
-[gun zapping continues]
-[Mason chuckling]
Fire and forget.
[alarm blaring]
[electronic buzzing]
[Mason] Hmm?
What the fuck?
You clever little bastard.
[music fades]
Hmm. I was worried this might happen.
Well, Mr. Mason,
there's only one thing for it.
We're gonna have to go mobile.
The all new TT-15
with gas-cooled auto-cannon,
armored chassis,
and the same targeting tech
that navy drones carry.
Now that is what I call tool use.
[sighing heavily] How much?
[man] Right, well,
we've recovered four of the TT6s,
but it says here you had five.
Ah, well, fucking rats trashed them.
[sighing] I'm afraid
I'll still have to report them missing.
[man] Good luck with that TT-15!
[Mason straining]
[grunting, groaning]
[clattering]
[electronic warbling]
[ominous music playing]
Bloody hell.
[TT-15 trilling]
Fuck.
[guns firing]
[Mason] Oh, um,
thank you.
Carry on.
Good boy.
[dramatic music playing]
[yawning]
Bloody hell.
Welcome to the ratpocalypse.
[guns firing]
-[suspenseful music playing]
-[rat yelping]
[rats screaming]
[squelching]
[rat moaning]
[rat screaming]
Christ on a bike.
[guns firing]
[guns zapping]
Ah, fucking…
Fuck.
[intense music playing]
[rats squeaking]
[guns zapping]
[rat yelling]
[rats yelling]
[guns zapping]
[rat screaming]
[music reaches crescendo]
[music stops]
[clattering]
[sizzling]
[somber music playing]
[Mason] Christ.
Like World War fucking IV.
[TT-15 trilling]
[suspenseful music playing]
[heart beating]
[suspenseful music swelling]
[gun firing]
[electronic warbling]
Take that, you nasty bastard.
[rats squeaking]
[uplifting music playing]
[handle squeaking]
[rat squeaking]
I salute your courage, sir.
-[rat squeaking]
-[slurping]
[coughing] Ugh.
[coughing] Bloody hell.
[hoarsely] That's good.
So good.
[rats squeaking]
[dramatic bagpipe music playing]
[phone beeping]
[Mason] Customer service, please.
Hello, this is Mason.
[chuckling] Aye, that's right.
That one. Yeah.
I just need to cancel a check.
[chuckling]
[music fades]
[electronic warbling]
[closing theme music playing]
[music fades]