[opening theme music playing]
[electronic warbling]
[suspenseful music playing]
We got these fuckers now.
We're gonna lose comms in there. [sighs]
[radio beeps]
Raptor Base, this is Delta Zero Three.
We have positive ID on the hostage.
[man on radio]
Delta Zero Three, understood.
The status of hostage?
Still breathing.
We followed the insurgents
to a tunnel system.
[man] Delta Zero Three, stand by.
It's getting kinda late.
Maybe we should back trail and break camp.
Wait till light.
That hostage looked like
he was in pretty bad shape.
[sighs]
It's always fucking night in a cave.
-Why are you such a pussy, Spence?
-Why are you such a dick, Dilman?
Get ready to move.
[man] Delta Zero Three,
secure hostage and proceed to exfil.
[man 2] Received, Raptor Base.
Delta Zero Three, over.
Beaumont, on point.
One beam, no white light.
Everyone, go goggles.
Spence,
I want IR markers at 25-meter intervals.
[Spencer] Roger that.
[suspenseful music playing]
[music intensifies]
Oh, I feel like a fat, fucking target
of opportunity up here.
Don't worry. I've got your back, donkey.
[Beaumont] Stop calling me that.
[Dilman] Okay, okay.
Soon as you stop fucking donkeys.
I told you, I was just petting it.
It was scared. What was I supposed to do?
All right.
Cut the bullshit. We're on the job.
Sarge.
[suspenseful music swells]
Weird shit, man.
What is it?
Some sort of lichen.
-Is that normal in a cave?
-Fuck if I know. I'm from Rhode Island.
[Beaumont] Sarge. Body.
[Sarge] Harper.
-Set security.
-Roger.
[Harper] A military-aged male.
No discerning marks of trauma.
[Beaumont] No trauma?
Then where'd his fucking face go?
[Sarge] The hostage.
Goddammit.
What the actual fuck?
[man] Sarge, I got two more over here.
[Sarge] These must be the insurgents.
Didn't we just see these guys?
What kinda weapon
does that to a person, huh?
Fuck this shit.
-[guns firing]
-[indistinct shouting]
[explosion]
We still have a mission.
Let's get this done. [exhales]
[whispering] Sarge,
the hostage was the mission.
We should take him home.
Harper, up.
[suspenseful music swells]
[squelching]
-[Beaumont] Hmm? [grunts]
-[chittering]
[Beaumont gasps]
The fuck you doing?
[unsettling music playing]
-Something's on me. Get it off!
-Shut the fuck up.
[chittering]
[screeching]
What the fuck?
[creature warbling]
[creature squeals]
It's got a fucking face or something.
[chittering grows louder]
[intense music playing]
No. No, no, no, no, no.
[Harper] Shit.
Fall back.
-[Beaumont] They're everywhere.
-[Spencer] Fuck this!
[Beaumont] Fuck. Shit!
[Sarge] Stone, light 'em up!
[Beaumont] Jesus!
[grunts, screams]
Beaumont!
-[screaming]
-[chomping, squelching]
[Sarge] Give me your hand! Fuck!
[Sarge grunts]
-Cover me.
-On me!
On your right!
Coming on your left.
Check right!
Reloading!
[gun firing]
[grunting]
[screaming]
[straining, groaning]
[squelching]
Sarge!
[Sarge] Let's go! Go!
-[Spencer] Dilman, let's go!
-[Dilman] Moving!
[Sarge] Move your ass! Let's go!
[Spencer grunts]
[music fades]
Jesus fuck,
those things ate Beaumont! [panting]
Where's Dilman?
[footsteps approaching]
[Dilman gasping, coughing]
[squelching]
[grunting, groaning]
-[Harper] Holy shit.
-[gasping]
-[Harper] Dilman--
-[Sarge] Hey!
[Harper] Fuck!
Dilman!
I could have helped him.
No. You couldn't have.
The bugs aren't following us.
They must only guard the tunnels.
Guard what?
[otherworldly moaning]
[ominous music playing]
[otherworldly whispering]
[Spencer] What in God's name
is this place?
That sound…
It's coming from…
[Harper] And what's making it?
[indistinct shouting]
We're soldiers,
not fucking archaeologists.
Those fuckers.
Sarge, for shit's sake--
-[man grunts]
-[man 2] Hey!
We got bigger problems.
Cannibal roaches with human faces
and a giant fucking alien temple.
-[Sarge shushing]
-[breath shuddering]
[man 2 grunts]
[panting]
Okay. We gotta get the fuck out of here.
[Harper] There's a tunnel over there.
-[Spencer breathing heavily]
-Could be the way to the surface.
[Sarge] Let's go!
…and my salvation. I shall not fear.
-[Harper] Spencer.
-The Lord is my light.
God is dead.
Embrace the suck. We gotta move.
[suspenseful music playing]
[Sarge grunting]
[otherworldly groaning]
[chittering]
[clattering]
[intense music playing]
Contact rear!
[creatures screeching]
-Go, go, go!
-[Spencer] Moving!
[Harper] Covering!
[creature screeches]
[Spencer] Fuck.
-[Sarge] Frag out!
-[Harper] Move it!
[Spencer] Reloading.
[Sarge] Move it!
[Spencer grunts]
[screams]
-[grunting, screaming]
-[squelching]
-Spence!
-[Sarge] He's gone! Let's go!
[creatures screeching]
[music fades]
[Sarge breathing heavily]
I'm out of ammo.
Down to one grenade. You?
Just this.
[Harper breathing heavily]
Might save the last round
for myself though.
[chain clanking]
[otherworldly whispering]
[Harper] That voice…
What the fuck is that?
[otherworldly groaning]
It's coming from…
from in there.
Okay. So let's get moving
in the opposite fucking direction.
[tense music playing]
[Harper] Sarge.
Sarge!
Sarge, what the fuck are you doing?
[otherworldly whispering continues]
[chains clanking]
[creature grunts]
[creature groaning]
[breath shuddering] How? What?
How?
No.
[squelching]
[Harper] No, no, no.
No, no, no, no.
[suspenseful music swelling]
Sarge, what…
[creature grunting]
[high-pitched screeching]
[Harper yelling, screaming]
No. Stop!
[screaming]
[creature groaning]
[Harper whimpering, screaming]
[creature] Release me.
Release me.
-Release me.
-[Harper whimpering]
[creature] Release me.
Sarge!
-Stop! Stop! [grunts]
-[creature] Release me.
-Release me.
-[Harper] Don't do this.
-[creature] Release me. Release me.
-[Harper] Sarge. Put it down!
-[creature] Release me.
-Stop!
-[Harper] Stop. No! No!
[creature] Release me.
[echoing] Release me.
Release me.
Fuck you!
[gun firing]
[creature] Release me.
Release me.
Release me…
[ominous music playing]
[Harper whispering in alien language]
[ominous music swelling]
[electronic warbling]
[closing theme music playing]